# Gabriel Pelosi Junior Back End Developer



https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabrielpelosi-92a578177/ gabriel.pelosi.2020@gmail.com gabrielpelosi.netlify.app

### **About Me**

Dedicated developer with experience in the payment industry. Consider myself a critical and mature team worker who enjoys challenging situations. Solving problems in the best way possible is what motivates me to learn more and build a great professional experience.

# **Work Experience**



#### **Junior Back End Developer**

Planet Payment, a global company that provides integrated payment solutions, hospitality and retail software and global VAT refunds.

## September 2022 to now (8 months)

- Worked on a payment gateway to provide digitalized wallets, alternative payment methods, and global VAT refunds for customers around de world.
- The gateway was built in Java with Spring Boot and MSSQL database.
- Also worked in a gateway platform to integrate some company systems and provide to merchants one single application for in-store or ecommerce transactions.
- The gateway platform was built with Spring Webflux, Kafka, CockroachDB, and AuthO. The whole environment was deployed on AWS company cloud.
- Developed soft skills such as communication, critical thinking, and how to better focus on remote work



## **Full stack Developer Internship**

Planet Payment

#### March 2022 to August 2022 (6 months)

- Worked in an internal company software to manage configurations and business processes.
- The software was built in a ReactJs front-end application and a Spring Boot back end to serve all the relevant data to the UI.
- Improved monitoring and managing tasks due to the automatization of many processes like creating new processes, retrieving failed processes, and updating configurations

# **Education History**



## **Graduation of Software Engineering**

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto (ISEP)

## September 2018 to July 2022

- Got introduced to teamwork
- I started on basic fundaments to advanced web development
- Learned to apply design patterns in projects
- Could also learn how to deploy applications using CI/CD and docker

# **Complementary Courses**



Microservices: Clean Architecture, DDD, SAGA, Outbox & Kafka

Udemy

July 2022 to January 2023

This course was a good approach to getting introduced to the design patterns for microservices and Kafka.



**Build Reactive MicroServices using Spring WebFlux/SpringBoot** 

Udemy

July 2022 to now

This course was great to get started with spring web flux for microservices. Learned how to develop reactive modules, unit and integration tests.

## **Relevant Skills**

#### **Technical skills**

- Java
- Spring Boot and Web flux
- Docker
- MSSQL
- Design Patterns
- GitHub Actions
- AuthO
- Kafka
- AWS

## Languages

- Portuguese
  - Native
- English
  - Advanced